Ian Waller

IT Director at Connect Education & Care

nikki.ianw@gmail.com

Summary

Creative, passionate, commercially focused, IT Executive with a "can do" attitude and proven track record of success. Calm under pressure, used to working in fast pace business environments, where IT is recognised as a critical enabler. Consistently builds high performing teams.

Substantial Multichannel Retail, eCommerce and Supply Chain experience. Career highlights include: Launch of two eCommerce Platforms, Implementation of Warehouse Management System, Outsourcing of Supply Chain capability, Implementation and Upgrade of ERP, Systems integrations following acquisitions and Migration to Dual Data Centre.

- Transformation of IT capability to enable delivery of business plan.
- Step change improvement in employee engagement scores.
- Increased internal customer satisfaction scores.
- Creation of blended delivery model, using internal resources and vendors, to resolve capacity and skills requirements.

Experience

IT Director at Connect Education & Care

January 2013 - Present (4 years 3 months)

Connect Education & Care (trading as "The Consortium" and "West Mercia Supplies") is the market-leading eCommerce / Catalogue business retailing into schools, nurseries and care homes. Turnover c.£65m. Member of executive team, reporting to Managing Director, responsible for IT & Facilities; appointed as part of new leadership team following acquisition by Connect Group PLC, to help maximise business growth through use of technology. EBITDA has grown from £6.9m to £9m against a declining / flat market.

- Talent Management of 20 employees across IT Solutions, IT Service and Facilities.
- Transformation of IT capability, including organisation redesign, moving from perceived risk to trusted partner, with track record of success.
- Introduction of project governance and software development lifecycle, including IT Service Management best practice.
- Working as part of Group IT Leadership forum, alongside other divisional IT Directors.
- Member of eCommerce Advisory Board, alongside key executive colleagues from within Connect Education & Care, Connect Group PLC and external expert advisors.

Project Management Lead at Wincor Nixdorf

October 2011 - January 2013 (1 year 4 months)

Wincor Nixdorf is a leading global technology vendor in Banking and Retail. UK turnover c.£11m. Reporting to Head of Professional Services, responsible for heading-up project delivery to all Customers within UK Retail Professional Services; appointed as part of new leadership team to transform UK Retail business.

- Working at board level within top UK Retail organisations.
- Leading teams of direct reports (Project Managers, Business Analysts, Developers and Testers) and matrix management of other international, multi-location, resources within Wincor Nixdorf, also management of international supplier resources.
- Management of multiple concurrent projects and budgets.

IT Manager - Application Delivery at House of Fraser

February 1999 - October 2011 (12 years 9 months)

House of Fraser is the UK's leading Department Store. Turnover c.£1.2bn. Reporting to IT Director, responsible for all aspects of Customer facing IT; including eCommerce, EPoS & customer kiosks. Originally appointed as Project Manager for EPoS, promoted to Finance & HR Systems Manager, finally promoted to IT Manager – Multichannel.

- Hugely technical and commercially focused role; working at executive board level on IT Strategy.
- Matrix management of teams up to 40 people, including internal, outsourced and supplier resources.
- Talent Management of highly skilled development team of 16 (comprising Project Managers, Business Analysts, Developers & Testers).

Systems Development Manager at Early Learning Centre

March 1997 - February 1999 (2 years)

Responsible for all systems development, including EPoS, Merchandise Management and Data Warehousing. Initially recruited as Senior Analyst Programmer, but then promoted to Systems Development Manager.

Senior Analyst Programmer at Bluebird Toys

April 1996 - February 1997 (11 months)

Analyst Programmer at Endsleigh Insurance Services Ltd

March 1994 - March 1996 (2 years 1 month)

Volunteer Experience

School Governor at Broad Town Church of England Primary School

October 2011 - December 2015

http://www.broadtown.wilts.sch.uk/wilts/primary/broadtown

Projects

House of Fraser eCommerce

January 2007 to October 2007

Members:Ian Waller, Colette Wilson, Ian Jindal, James Park, My Linh Tran, Paul Malins, Martina Bode, Tim Crampin, Peter Callaway

Project to launch House of Fraser eCommerce (Demandware) offering to customers, from store front through to goods fulfillment and customer services.

House of Fraser Wedding List

August 2008 to July 2009

Members: Ian Waller, Martina Bode, Rob Davey, Colette Wilson, My Linh Tran

The creation and launch of new multichannel Wedding List service.

Google Local Shopping

September 2011 to Present

Members: Ian Waller, David Fiddes, Anna Lenartowska, Dan Seymour

Integration of products, stores and stock levels to Google for inclusion in local shopping search of products

M&S in-store TSOP (Touch Screen Order Point)

July 2012 to Present

Members: Ian Waller, Andrew Bull, Frieder Hansen, Julie Fynn

Project from design through to delivery of leading edge in-store transactional kiosk (Polytouch) as part of Marks & Spencer multichannel growth programme

Oracle eBusiness HR/Payroll

November 2002 to Present

Members:Ian Waller, Mick Goodyear

Implementation of Oracle eBusiness suite HRMS and Payroll to replace legacy systems

House of Fraser Gift Card

November 2009 to Present

Members: Ian Waller, Ajay Sethi, Mike Roberts

Creation and launch of House of Fraser first Gift Card to replace paper based gift vouchers

House of Fraser Order in Store

September 2010 to Present

Members: Ian Waller, Vanessa Stamp, Anthony Wicks, Dan Seymour, Chris Randall

Design and delivery of in-store ability to order goods from online store. Project covered all aspects or hardware and software.

New Magento eCommerce Platform

August 2013 to Present

Members: Ian Waller, Stephen Leyton, Duncan Ball, Stuart Taylor

Launch of new eCommerce platform using Magento Enterprise with thepixel

eProcurement Hub

February 2015 to Present

Members:Ian Waller, Scott Goddard, Nicholas J H Evans, Duncan Ball, Stuart Taylor

Leading edge procurement integration with customer systems, thereby saving valuable time.

Warehouse Management System (HighJump)

October 2014 to Present

Members:Ian Waller, Scott Goddard, Don Rigdon, PMP MBA, David Houser

Replacement of legacy Warehouse Management System with HighJump Warehouse Advantage

Freight Carrier Integration

April 2016 to Present

Members:Ian Waller

Following tender process for new freight partner, successful integration, across two Warehouse Management Systems, with TNT.

Skills & Expertise

E-commerce

Project Delivery

Retail

Outsourcing

Management

ERP

Program Management

Oracle

ITIL

Stakeholder Management

Change Management

SaaS

Data Warehousing

Project Management

IT Strategy

CRM

Project Planning

Business Analysis

PRINCE2

Budgets

Strategic Planning

Professional Services

People Management

Budgeting

Leadership

Team Leadership

Talent Management

Talent Acquisition

Strategy

Software as a Service (SaaS)

Enterprise Resource Planning (ERP)

Customer Relationship Management (CRM)

Recruiting

Education

University of Central Lancashire

BSc(Hons), Business Information Technology, 1989 - 1993

Grade: 2:1

Quanta Training

MSP Foundation & Practitioner, Programme Management

Quanta Training

PRINCE2 Foundation & Practitioner, Project Management

Quanta Training

ITIL v3 Foundation, IT Service Management

Ian Waller

IT Director at Connect Education & Care

nikki.ianw@gmail.com



2 people have recommended lan

"Ian is a strong communicator, and gets his point across simply. He manages complex projects efficiently, keeping to schedule, with tight P&L management. Ian gets disparate teams together to execute with great success. He built rapport well and became an excellent trusted advisor to our customers."

— Adrian Tate, managed Ian at Wincor Nixdorf

"I worked with Ian during my previous tenure at House of Fraser. Ian's passion, drive and deep knowledge made him really stand out amongst his peers. His determination and focus was a key factor in the successful delivery of a number of significant retail projects including the high profile order-in-store initiative."

— Chris Randall, IT Manager - Infrastructure Solutions/Outsource Transition Manager, House of Fraser, worked directly with Ian at House of Fraser

Contact Ian on LinkedIn